<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>medoix</title><link>https://medoix.com/</link><description>Recent content on medoix</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 15:46:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://medoix.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Increase Terminal Size Font of 4k Device</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2021/04/increase-terminal-size-font-of-4k-device/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 15:46:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2021/04/increase-terminal-size-font-of-4k-device/</guid><description>When booting a new Linux install on a 4k HiDPI screen the terminal font size becomes so small that it is near impossible to read.
In order to increase the font size i found this neat little setting that does just that, now you can read your terminal before you startx.
Edit /etc/vconsole.conf and add/replace with the following to get larger font on the next boot.
FONT=latarcyrheb-sun32</description></item><item><title>Fix Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) File Permissions</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2021/01/fix-windows-subsystem-for-linux-wsl-file-permissions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 11:55:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2021/01/fix-windows-subsystem-for-linux-wsl-file-permissions/</guid><description>Windows 10 and WSL (windows Subsystem Linux) is very useful when wanting to run linux type tasks on your Windows 10 machine instead of booting up a dedicated Linux Virtual Machine for example. One downside is that Windows 10 WSL does a terrible job at emulating Linux permissions when it mounts the directories stored locally on the Windows filesystem.
There are two fixes we can do here to make this much nicer&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Docker Everything List</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2019/11/docker-everything-list/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 09:16:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2019/11/docker-everything-list/</guid><description>Docker Everything All of the projects i work on these i automatically create a Dockerfile to build a reliable and reusable image i can run locally to test or deploy to a prod kube cluster or docker host to run permanenetly and this got me thinking&amp;hellip; can i run my day to day tools and systems in Docker?
The answer is almost always yes! Therfore below is my list of tools and services i use daily/randomly That’s are one liners to get going in a container.</description></item><item><title>Linux Desktop Showing Content of Home Directory</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2019/01/linux-desktop-showing-content-of-home-directory/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 08:22:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2019/01/linux-desktop-showing-content-of-home-directory/</guid><description>Ever had that awkward moment where you login to your Linux desktop and there are a LOT of files on the desktop that you are not sure about (even DOT files).
This usually means something has gone haywire with your configuration and the desktop is now set to a different folder (different than the default /home/user/Desktop folder).
This happened to me and i believe it was because i deleted my Desktop folder (don&amp;rsquo;t ask) and it seems that XDG just took it upon itself to set its new location to my home (~/) directory and therefore i was seeing dot files and all the different folders associated.</description></item><item><title>Prevent VirtualBox Guest Syncing Time with Host</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2019/01/prevent-virtualbox-guest-syncing-time-with-host/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 07:58:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2019/01/prevent-virtualbox-guest-syncing-time-with-host/</guid><description>Recently i was creating a few different guest machines inside my VirtualBox host (Windows) and noticed an odd theme of APT not being able to update due to the resources obtained being from the future! (i am a time traveler). This usually screams out one thing.
Check the system time!
Upon checking my guest machines time it was in fact days behind where it should be, this meant that even with the VirtualBox guest tools installed AND the &amp;ldquo;Hardware clock in UTC&amp;rdquo; option selected under Motherboard, the guest was still not getting the right time.</description></item><item><title>Mac OSX Sudo With Fingerprint</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2017/11/mac-osx-sudo-with-fingerprint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 12:14:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2017/11/mac-osx-sudo-with-fingerprint/</guid><description>Have a shiny new Macbook Pro with touch bar? Sick and tired of typing your local password each time you wanrt to sudo anythiong within the terminal?
Well boy do i have an awesome solution for you!
Open up terminal and edit the following file (this will be the last time you need to enter your password for sudo)
sudo nano /etc/pam.d/sudo Add the following at the top of the file</description></item><item><title>Disable Bonjour in Cyberduck</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2015/08/disable-bonjour-in-cyberduck/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 12:32:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2015/08/disable-bonjour-in-cyberduck/</guid><description>I used Cyberduck on Mac OS X for quite a lot of tasks including talking to S3 buckets or even SFTP&amp;rsquo;ing into my Linux servers.
Every time I load up Cyberduck, I get flooded with Bonjour Growl notifications. Since I never use Bonjour with Cyberduck, I figured it’s acceptable to disable it. It’s a simple Terminal command, like so many other things are in the Mac world. To disable Bonjour, fire up Terminal and execute this command:</description></item><item><title>Turnigy 9x 'Resistor Fix' Trainer Port</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2015/07/turnigy-9x-resistor-fix-trainer-port/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 18:40:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2015/07/turnigy-9x-resistor-fix-trainer-port/</guid><description>The &amp;lsquo;resistor fix&amp;rsquo; solves the problem of needing to unplug the wireless module in order to use the trainer port.
It involves cutting a trace on a PCB inside the transmitter, and soldering a resistor (usually a 1kOhm resistor) in series by bridging the cut trace.
Why do you need to unplug the wireless module in the first place?
A Little More Theory The trainer port on the 9X contains a switch (that triggers when a plug is inserted into the trainer jack) that powers off the wireless module to ensure the 9X no longer transmits its signal.</description></item><item><title>PBCopy From SSH to Local OSX</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2014/11/pbcopy-from-ssh-to-local-osx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2014 11:43:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2014/11/pbcopy-from-ssh-to-local-osx/</guid><description>I have been wondering for a long time how i could copy large config files or any file for that matter from nano/vi inside an SSH session to my local clipboard (OSX). As you can imagine copying one section at a time from your favourite text editor has long been a pain in the rear end.
The trick uses netcat (nc) to pipe text over an SSH connection to a local listener that passes it to pbcopy.</description></item><item><title>Make Sudo Sessions Last Longer in Linux</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2013/08/make-sudo-sessions-last-longer-in-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 08:52:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2013/08/make-sudo-sessions-last-longer-in-linux/</guid><description>When you run sudo in Ubuntu, your administrative privileges last for 15 minutes by default so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to type in your password with every command. If that is too long or short for your tastes, you can change it with a simple tweak.
Run the following command in a Terminal:
sudo visudo Scroll down to the line that looks like this:
Defaults env_reset and change it to this:</description></item></channel></rss>