<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Terminal on medoix</title><link>https://medoix.com/tags/terminal/</link><description>Recent content in Terminal on medoix</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 08:52:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://medoix.com/tags/terminal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Make Sudo Sessions Last Longer in Linux</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2013/08/make-sudo-sessions-last-longer-in-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 08:52:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2013/08/make-sudo-sessions-last-longer-in-linux/</guid><description>When you run sudo in Ubuntu, your administrative privileges last for 15 minutes by default so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to type in your password with every command. If that is too long or short for your tastes, you can change it with a simple tweak.
Run the following command in a Terminal:
sudo visudo Scroll down to the line that looks like this:
Defaults env_reset and change it to this:</description></item><item><title>Make Password Asterisks Visible in your Mac or Linux Terminal</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2013/08/make-password-asterisks-visible-in-your-mac-or-linux-terminal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 08:41:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2013/08/make-password-asterisks-visible-in-your-mac-or-linux-terminal/</guid><description>When you run a command with sudo in Linux, the terminal prompts you to type in your password and doesn&amp;rsquo;t give you any visual feedback. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick tweak that&amp;rsquo;ll bring back those familiar asterisks (*) when you type in your password.
I&amp;rsquo;m a fast typer, so when I mess up my password, I have to start over from scratch. With asterisks, it&amp;rsquo;s a lot easier—and seeing as no one&amp;rsquo;s looking over my shoulder in my home office, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how obscured my password is.</description></item><item><title>Stop OS X Terminal SSH Timeout</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2012/02/stop-os-x-terminal-ssh-timeout/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 07:57:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2012/02/stop-os-x-terminal-ssh-timeout/</guid><description>There are three ways to do this using the ServerAliveInterval to send data along every few seconds. Replace the &amp;ldquo;10&amp;rdquo; with the number of seconds between pings.
From least to most global:
1. Add the option on the command line:
ssh -o ServerAliveInterval=10 keepsdroppingme.com 2. Add the option to your personal ssh config by creating/editing ~/.ssh/config:
# This is ~/.ssh/config # For all hosts ServerAliveInterval 10 # For a selection of hosts Host keepsdroppingme.</description></item><item><title>Get External (WAN) IP Address from Command Line in Linux</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2012/02/get-external-wan-ip-address-from-command-line-in-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 18:14:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2012/02/get-external-wan-ip-address-from-command-line-in-linux/</guid><description>Many services and applications require you to know your external (WAN) IP address. There are plenty of web sites that allow you to do this, but here are a couple of simple ways to do this from the command line in Linux.
The first method uses the cURL utility, which is basically a command-line utility for retrieving data using URL syntax. In Ubuntu or Debian, you can install cURL from the repositories using the command:</description></item><item><title>Code Syntax Highlighting in VI (Linux Editor)</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2011/08/code-syntax-highlighting-in-vi-linux-editor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 13:53:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2011/08/code-syntax-highlighting-in-vi-linux-editor/</guid><description>I recently wrote about how to enable syntax highlighting in the linux editor NANO.
Below i will explain how to enable such features in VI, as they are built in it is much easier.
Move to your home directory and create/open the settings file:
cd vi .vimrc Enable syntax highlighting:
syntax on Save using:
:wq! You will now have syntax highlighting enabled when using vi/vim as your editor of choice.</description></item><item><title>Code Syntax Highlighting in Nano (Linux Editor)</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2011/08/code-syntax-highlighting-in-nano-linux-editor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 18:58:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2011/08/code-syntax-highlighting-in-nano-linux-editor/</guid><description>Today i was looking for a way to enable extended code syntax highlighting in the linux text editor nano, out of the box nano comes with limited functionality to do this. I will tell you how to download the needed files and add them to the nano configuration and you will be looking at much prettier code in no time.
Firstly we need the syntax files: DOWNLOAD HERE
Secondly we need to extract the contents and move to the correct location:</description></item></channel></rss>