<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ubuntu on medoix</title><link>https://medoix.com/tags/ubuntu/</link><description>Recent content in Ubuntu on medoix</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 15:33:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://medoix.com/tags/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Remove Old Kernels in Ubuntu</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2012/11/remove-old-kernels-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 15:33:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2012/11/remove-old-kernels-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>To get started, open Terminal. When it opens, run the commands below to view your current running kernel.
uname -r Next, take notes of your current kernel. DO NOT REMOVE THIS!
Next, type the command below to view / list all installed kernels on your system.
dpkg --list | grep linux-image Next, find all the kernels that which number are lower than your current kernel. When you know which kernel to remove, continue below to remove it.</description></item><item><title>Tor Hidden Service on Ubuntu</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2012/01/tor-hidden-service-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 20:45:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2012/01/tor-hidden-service-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>NOTE: This article does not explain how to setup apache or any other services apart from the tor application for hidden_service.
I have recently been migrating all of my browsing, email and communications etc through the Tor Network.
One of the cool features of the onion router is the ability to setup what is referred to as a hidden service. This is just what it sounds like, a domain (16characters.onion) randomly generated and completely anonymous through the Tor network can be configured to point to a local service port.</description></item><item><title>Disable Translation Packages in Ubuntu</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2012/01/disable-translation-packages-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 07:40:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2012/01/disable-translation-packages-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>To disable downloading translations, create a file named /etc/apt/apt.conf.d/99translations &amp;amp; put the following in it:
Acquire::Languages &amp;#34;none&amp;#34;; You may also need to remove existing translation files in /var/lib/apt/lists/ I personally just empty the lists folder and do an apt-get update</description></item></channel></rss>