<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apple OSX on medoix</title><link>https://medoix.com/categories/apple-osx/</link><description>Recent content in Apple OSX on medoix</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 12:14:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://medoix.com/categories/apple-osx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mac OSX Sudo With Fingerprint</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2017/11/mac-osx-sudo-with-fingerprint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 12:14:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2017/11/mac-osx-sudo-with-fingerprint/</guid><description>Have a shiny new Macbook Pro with touch bar? Sick and tired of typing your local password each time you wanrt to sudo anythiong within the terminal?
Well boy do i have an awesome solution for you!
Open up terminal and edit the following file (this will be the last time you need to enter your password for sudo)
sudo nano /etc/pam.d/sudo Add the following at the top of the file</description></item><item><title>Disable Bonjour in Cyberduck</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2015/08/disable-bonjour-in-cyberduck/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 12:32:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2015/08/disable-bonjour-in-cyberduck/</guid><description>I used Cyberduck on Mac OS X for quite a lot of tasks including talking to S3 buckets or even SFTP&amp;rsquo;ing into my Linux servers.
Every time I load up Cyberduck, I get flooded with Bonjour Growl notifications. Since I never use Bonjour with Cyberduck, I figured it’s acceptable to disable it. It’s a simple Terminal command, like so many other things are in the Mac world. To disable Bonjour, fire up Terminal and execute this command:</description></item><item><title>PBCopy From SSH to Local OSX</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2014/11/pbcopy-from-ssh-to-local-osx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2014 11:43:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2014/11/pbcopy-from-ssh-to-local-osx/</guid><description>I have been wondering for a long time how i could copy large config files or any file for that matter from nano/vi inside an SSH session to my local clipboard (OSX). As you can imagine copying one section at a time from your favourite text editor has long been a pain in the rear end.
The trick uses netcat (nc) to pipe text over an SSH connection to a local listener that passes it to pbcopy.</description></item><item><title>Permanent Delete on OSX (Windows Shift + Delete Alternative)</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2013/07/permanent-delete-on-osx-windows-shift-delete-alternative/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 09:54:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2013/07/permanent-delete-on-osx-windows-shift-delete-alternative/</guid><description>Create an Automator service or application to facilitate executing the rm shell command, which will permanently delete files or folders and skip the trash.
For example, start with creating a new Service in Automator.app.
Select files or folders as input, you probably also want to limit the availability of this service to the Finder app. Optionally, but highly recommended, first add an Ask for Confirmation step to the workflow.</description></item><item><title>Stop OS X Terminal SSH Timeout</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2012/02/stop-os-x-terminal-ssh-timeout/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 07:57:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2012/02/stop-os-x-terminal-ssh-timeout/</guid><description>There are three ways to do this using the ServerAliveInterval to send data along every few seconds. Replace the &amp;ldquo;10&amp;rdquo; with the number of seconds between pings.
From least to most global:
1. Add the option on the command line:
ssh -o ServerAliveInterval=10 keepsdroppingme.com 2. Add the option to your personal ssh config by creating/editing ~/.ssh/config:
# This is ~/.ssh/config # For all hosts ServerAliveInterval 10 # For a selection of hosts Host keepsdroppingme.</description></item><item><title>Mac OSX Lion – Remove “all my files” from Finder</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2012/01/mac-osx-lion-remove-all-my-files-from-finder/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 11:01:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2012/01/mac-osx-lion-remove-all-my-files-from-finder/</guid><description>Finder on Mac OS X Lion by default is always showing “All My Files” on every new window. Well to be honest not even once I found it useful, never used it since the first install.
Even if you are a geeky Terminal fan, there are always times that you start up Finder, and you need to get faster to your important files. Most of the times I am looking for something in the Documents folder/subfolders, so here is how I have set it as the default Finder directory:</description></item><item><title>Pop-Up Notifications to iTunes</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2011/11/pop-up-notifications-to-itunes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 09:59:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2011/11/pop-up-notifications-to-itunes/</guid><description>Mac: Usually, if you want to find out what’s playing in iTunes, you either need to right-click the icon or open it.
Macworld found a method that only requires a little work in Terminal to enable a small pop-up on your dock showing the currently-playing track.The process is simple, but only works in OS X Lion.
First, boot up Terminal in your Utilities folder on a Mac, then, type:
defaults write com.</description></item><item><title>Enable VNC/Management on OSX by SSH</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2011/11/enable-vnc/management-on-osx-by-ssh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 09:56:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2011/11/enable-vnc/management-on-osx-by-ssh/</guid><description>I had the VNC based remote access feature of OS X enabled on 10.7 but somehow it got switched off. I fiddled around a bit and figured out how to enable remote access from a remote SSH shell. Note that these instructions will lead to manual configuration and you will not be able to enable/disabled the services from the System Preferences anymore. In my case I used this to get in when I needed to but latter switched it back off and used the System Preferences setting.</description></item><item><title>Change DeployStudio Wallpaper</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2011/09/change-deploystudio-wallpaper/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 09:40:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2011/09/change-deploystudio-wallpaper/</guid><description>I have been doing quite a bit of Mac OS X Image work lately and have found DeployStudio to be THE best FREE and easy to customise solution for doing this.
One thing i wanted to do was change the default wallpaper for the DeployStudioRuntime.nbi that is created and used as a windows Pre Environment equivalent.
I achieved this by going into the DeployStudioRuntime.nbi folder located on the server at:</description></item><item><title>Prevent .DS_Store File Creation on Network Volumes</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2011/08/prevent-.ds_store-file-creation-on-network-volumes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 07:25:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2011/08/prevent-.ds_store-file-creation-on-network-volumes/</guid><description>This KnowledgeBase article explains how to prevent OS X from creating new .DS_Store files when opening folders on remote volumes mounted using SMB/CIFS, AFP, NFS, and WebDAV. The creation of .DS_Store files (and more so, ._AppleDouble files which are not covered in this hint) is frequently the source of complaints against Mac users, who often leave a trail of these files scattered throughout the filesystem when &amp;ldquo;visiting&amp;rdquo; a Windows computer. Even with this hint in place, the .</description></item></channel></rss>