<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows OS on medoix</title><link>https://medoix.com/categories/windows-os/</link><description>Recent content in Windows OS on medoix</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 11:55:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://medoix.com/categories/windows-os/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fix Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) File Permissions</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2021/01/fix-windows-subsystem-for-linux-wsl-file-permissions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 11:55:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2021/01/fix-windows-subsystem-for-linux-wsl-file-permissions/</guid><description>Windows 10 and WSL (windows Subsystem Linux) is very useful when wanting to run linux type tasks on your Windows 10 machine instead of booting up a dedicated Linux Virtual Machine for example. One downside is that Windows 10 WSL does a terrible job at emulating Linux permissions when it mounts the directories stored locally on the Windows filesystem.
There are two fixes we can do here to make this much nicer&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Prevent VirtualBox Guest Syncing Time with Host</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2019/01/prevent-virtualbox-guest-syncing-time-with-host/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 07:58:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2019/01/prevent-virtualbox-guest-syncing-time-with-host/</guid><description>Recently i was creating a few different guest machines inside my VirtualBox host (Windows) and noticed an odd theme of APT not being able to update due to the resources obtained being from the future! (i am a time traveler). This usually screams out one thing.
Check the system time!
Upon checking my guest machines time it was in fact days behind where it should be, this meant that even with the VirtualBox guest tools installed AND the &amp;ldquo;Hardware clock in UTC&amp;rdquo; option selected under Motherboard, the guest was still not getting the right time.</description></item></channel></rss>