<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Programming on medoix</title><link>https://medoix.com/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in Programming on medoix</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2014 11:43:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://medoix.com/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PBCopy From SSH to Local OSX</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2014/11/pbcopy-from-ssh-to-local-osx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2014 11:43:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2014/11/pbcopy-from-ssh-to-local-osx/</guid><description>I have been wondering for a long time how i could copy large config files or any file for that matter from nano/vi inside an SSH session to my local clipboard (OSX). As you can imagine copying one section at a time from your favourite text editor has long been a pain in the rear end.
The trick uses netcat (nc) to pipe text over an SSH connection to a local listener that passes it to pbcopy.</description></item><item><title>Code Syntax Highlighting in VI (Linux Editor)</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2011/08/code-syntax-highlighting-in-vi-linux-editor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 13:53:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2011/08/code-syntax-highlighting-in-vi-linux-editor/</guid><description>I recently wrote about how to enable syntax highlighting in the linux editor NANO.
Below i will explain how to enable such features in VI, as they are built in it is much easier.
Move to your home directory and create/open the settings file:
cd vi .vimrc Enable syntax highlighting:
syntax on Save using:
:wq! You will now have syntax highlighting enabled when using vi/vim as your editor of choice.</description></item><item><title>Code Syntax Highlighting in Nano (Linux Editor)</title><link>https://medoix.com/posts/2011/08/code-syntax-highlighting-in-nano-linux-editor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 18:58:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://medoix.com/posts/2011/08/code-syntax-highlighting-in-nano-linux-editor/</guid><description>Today i was looking for a way to enable extended code syntax highlighting in the linux text editor nano, out of the box nano comes with limited functionality to do this. I will tell you how to download the needed files and add them to the nano configuration and you will be looking at much prettier code in no time.
Firstly we need the syntax files: DOWNLOAD HERE
Secondly we need to extract the contents and move to the correct location:</description></item></channel></rss>